[
    {
        "id": 1,
        "Question": "Which of the following is supported by Ruby?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Multiple Programming Paradigms",
            "b) Dynamic Type System",
            "c) Automatic Memory Management",
            "d) All of the Mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Ruby allow users to manipulate data structures called objects to build and execute programs."
    },
    {
        "id": 2,
        "Question": "Which of the following features does the 2.0 version of ruby supports?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Method keyword arguments",
            "b) New literals",
            "c) Security fixes",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Ruby supports all the features because it is a object oriented programming language."
    },
    {
        "id": 3,
        "Question": "Which of the following languages syntax matches with the Ruby’s syntax?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Perl",
            "b) PHP",
            "c) Java",
            "d) Jquery"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Ruby2.0 has several new added features and it is much stable than its older versions."
    },
    {
        "id": 4,
        "Question": "What is the extension used for saving the ruby file?",
        "Options": [
            "a) .ruby extension",
            "b) .rb extension",
            "c) .rrb extension",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Most of the syntax of perl language matches with that of Ruby’s."
    },
    {
        "id": 5,
        "Question": "Which of the following are valid floating point literal?",
        "Options": [
            "a) .5",
            "b) 2",
            "c) 0.5",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Ruby files must be saved with the extension .rb."
    },
    {
        "id": 6,
        "Question": "Which of the following datatypes are valid in Ruby?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Numbers",
            "b) Boolean",
            "c) String",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Ruby supports all the three (numbers,strings,boolean) data types."
    },
    {
        "id": 7,
        "Question": "What will any variable  evaluate to if it is of Boolean data type?",
        "Options": [
            "a) True",
            "b) Nil",
            "c) False",
            "d) Either True or False"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Boolean data types will give the value either as True or False depending on the condition."
    },
    {
        "id": 8,
        "Question": "Why can not we use quotation marks (‘ or “) with boolean?",
        "Options": [
            "a) It indicates that we are talking about a string",
            "b) It indicates that we are assining a value",
            "c) It indicates that that we are replacing boolean data type with string data type",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Quotation marks are used only with strings."
    },
    {
        "id": 9,
        "Question": "What is the size of an integer data type in ruby?",
        "Options": [
            "a) -230 to 230",
            "b) -230 to 2(30-1)",
            "c) -229 to 230",
            "d) -260 to 261"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Ruby differentiates between small and capital letters and their meaning."
    },
    {
        "id": 10,
        "Question": "7. What is the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\">boolean_1 = <span class=\"nu0\">77</span><span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span><span class=\"nu0\">78</span>\n   <span class=\"kw3\">puts</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>boolean_1<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Nil",
            "b) True",
            "c) False",
            "d) Error"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Integer ranges from -230 to 229 and lies in object of class Fixnum."
    },
    {
        "id": 11,
        "Question": "Objects of which class does the integer from the range -2^30 to 2^(30-1) belong to?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Bignum",
            "b) Octal",
            "c) Fixnum",
            "d) Binary"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: We can assingn a integer and a floating point value to a variable."
    },
    {
        "id": 12,
        "Question": "What does the notataion \\b stands for?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Escape",
            "b) Space",
            "c) Backspace",
            "d) Newline"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: As 77 is less than 78 hence the boolean value will be printed as true.\n\n\n\t\n\nOutput:\nTrue\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 13,
        "Question": "What is the sequence of ruby strings?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 16-bit bytes",
            "b) 8-bit bytes",
            "c) 10-bit bytes",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Integer within this range are objects of the class fixnum."
    },
    {
        "id": 14,
        "Question": "11. What is the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\">my_string=Ruby\n    <span class=\"kw3\">puts</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>my_string<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Ruby",
            "b) Nil",
            "c) Error",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: This notataion is used for backspace."
    },
    {
        "id": 15,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a valid datatype?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Float",
            "b) Integer",
            "c) Binary",
            "d) Timedate"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: They are simply the sequence of 8-bit bytes."
    },
    {
        "id": 16,
        "Question": "What is the range of octal notation (\\nnn)?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0-8",
            "b) 0-7",
            "c) 0-A",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Ruby should be written in double quotes inorder to indicate a string.\n\n\nOutput:\nError\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 17,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a valid library function?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Puts",
            "b) Print",
            "c) Gets",
            "d) Get"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: gets is used for taking input from the user."
    },
    {
        "id": 18,
        "Question": "Why is the library function ‘puts’used for?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Prints whatever is given and print it to the screen",
            "b) Prints whatever is given and insert a new(blank) line",
            "c) Gets input from the user",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Puts is a library function which prints and then insert a new blank line."
    },
    {
        "id": 19,
        "Question": "a) Error",
        "Options": [
            "b) Hey everyone we are learning Ruby",
            "c) Hey everyone",
            "d) Hey Everyone",
            "   We are learning Ruby"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Print prints whatever is given and puts in addition to printing it inserts a new blank line.\n\n\n        \n\nOutput:\nHey Everyone\nWe are learning Ruby\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 20,
        "Question": "For getting an input from the user which method is used?",
        "Options": [
            "a) get",
            "b) gets.chomp",
            "c) get-s",
            "d) chomp"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: No semicolon or parentheses is required."
    },
    {
        "id": 21,
        "Question": "Which sequence can be used to substitute the value of any ruby expression in a string?",
        "Options": [
            "a) #(expr)",
            "b) #{expr}",
            "c) #expr",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The method gets.chomp takes the input from the user."
    },
    {
        "id": 22,
        "Question": "Why is gets not preferred instead of gets.chomp?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Gets add an extra new line while chomp removes it",
            "b) Gets remove an extra new line",
            "c) Chomp erases the value stored in the variable",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: It will print and ask you to input the name and surname\n\n\nOutput:\n  What is your first name?\n  xyz(enter any name)\n  What is your surname?\n  wtu(enter your surname)\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 23,
        "Question": "11. What is the output of the the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\"> <span class=\"kw3\">puts</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"My name is #{Name}\"</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Error in compilation",
            "b) Name variable not defined earlier",
            "c) My name is #{Name}",
            "d) Undefined Error"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: #{expr} is valid."
    },
    {
        "id": 24,
        "Question": "13. What is the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\">Ans=Ruby\n    <span class=\"kw3\">puts</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"#[Ans] is an oop language\"</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Error, no output",
            "b) Ruby is an oop language",
            "c) Warning:already initialized constant Ans",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: gets.chomp will remove the extra blank space."
    },
    {
        "id": 25,
        "Question": "Which of the following is the valid string method?",
        "Options": [
            "a) The .length method",
            "b) The .upcase method",
            "c) The .downcase method",
            "d) The .irreverse method"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: There is no predefined method which can reverse an already reversed string."
    },
    {
        "id": 26,
        "Question": "3. What is the output of the following?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\"> <span class=\"st0\">\"Iam learning ruby language\"</span>.<span class=\"me1\">length</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 26",
            "b) 23",
            "c) 20",
            "d) 18"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The .length method is used to check number of characters, spaces and even symbols."
    },
    {
        "id": 27,
        "Question": "4. What is the output of the following?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\"> ruby.<span class=\"me1\">reverse</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Error in compilation",
            "b) ybur",
            "c) 4",
            "d) Undefined local variable ruby"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: It checks the number of blanks, number of characters and symbols in the given string.\n\n\n        \n\nOutput:\n26\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 28,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the following?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"st0\">\"Eric\"</span>.<span class=\"me1\">irreverse</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Eric",
            "b) cirE",
            "c) undefined method",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: String should always be in double quotes and then the .reverse method can be used.\n\n\n\t\n\nOutput:\nundefined local variable or method `ruby' for #<Context:0x7420ac>\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 29,
        "Question": "What does the .upcase method do?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Convert the string to uppercase",
            "b) Convert only lowercase string to uppercase and vice-versa",
            "c) Convert the string to lowercase",
            "d) None o the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: There is no predefined method named irreverse in ruby.\n\n\nOutput:\nundefined method `irreverse' for \"eric\":String\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 30,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"st0\">\"Ruby\"</span>.<span class=\"me1\">reverse</span>.<span class=\"me1\">upcase</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) RUBY",
            "b) ybuR",
            "c) YBUR",
            "d) YBUr"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: .upcase method is used to change the given string to uppercase."
    },
    {
        "id": 31,
        "Question": "8. What will be the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"st0\">\"I'am learning Ruby Language\"</span>.<span class=\"me1\">length</span>.<span class=\"me1\">reverse</span>.<span class=\"me1\">upcase</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 27",
            "b) egaugnal ybuR gninreal ma’I",
            "c) ERAUGNAL YBUR GNINREAL MA’I",
            "d) Undefined method `reverse’ for 27:Fixnum"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: First the given string is reversed and then .upcase method is used to capitalize it.\n\n\nOutput:\n\"YBUR\"\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 32,
        "Question": "9. What will be the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"st0\">\"I'am learning Ruby Language\"</span>.<span class=\"me1\">reverse</span>.<span class=\"me1\">upcase</span>.<span class=\"me1\">length</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 27",
            "b) egaugnal ybuR gninreal ma’I",
            "c) ERAUGNAL YBUR GNINREAL MA’I",
            "d) Undefined method `reverse’ for 27:Fixnum"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The .length method finds the length which is a number and can’t be reversed.\n\n\nOutput:\nundefined method `reverse' for 27:Fixnum\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 33,
        "Question": "11. What will we the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\"> <span class=\"st0\">\"I'am Learning RUBY Language\"</span>.<span class=\"me1\">downcase</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) iam learning ruby language",
            "b) i’AM lEARNING ruby lANGUAGE",
            "c) “i’am learning ruby language”",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The .reverse will reverse it then .upcase will capitalize it and .length method give the length.\n\n\nOutput:\n27\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 34,
        "Question": "12. What is the output of given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\"> <span class=\"kw3\">string</span>=<span class=\"st0\">\"I'am Learning RUBY Language\"</span>.<span class=\"me1\">downcase</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">string</span>.<span class=\"me1\">upcase</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Undefined method",
            "b) “I’AM LEARNING RUBY LANGUAGE”",
            "c) I’am Learning RUBY Language",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Changes everything to smallcase."
    },
    {
        "id": 35,
        "Question": "13. What will be the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"st0\">\"Come let's learn.reverse Ruby.length language\"</span>.<span class=\"me1\">upcase</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) nreal s’tel emoC 4 LANGUAGE",
            "b) Undefined error",
            "c) “COME LET’S LEARN.REVERSE RUBY.LENGTH LANGUAGE”",
            "d) None of the above"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Everything is changed to smallcase because of downcase method is used.\n\n\nOutput:\n\"i'am learning ruby language\"\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 36,
        "Question": "14. What will we the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\">I<span class=\"st0\">'am Learning RUBY Language.downcase</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) iam learning ruby language",
            "b) i’AM lEARNING ruby lANGUAGE",
            "c) “i’am learning ruby language”",
            "d) unterminated string meets end of file"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: First the given string is changed to uppercase and stored in variable named string and then the string is changed to uppercase.\n\n\nOutput:\n\"I'AM LEARNING RUBY LANGUAGE\"\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 37,
        "Question": "What is the use of .capitalize method?",
        "Options": [
            "a) It capitalizes the entire string",
            "b) It capitalize on the first letter of the string",
            "c) It capitalize the strings which are in small case",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The .capitalize method doesn’t change the whole string to uppercase, it just capitalizes the first letter."
    },
    {
        "id": 38,
        "Question": "What is the role of ! at the end of the capitalize method?",
        "Options": [
            "a) It is the syntax for using capitalize method",
            "b) It modifies the value stored in the variable",
            "c) It indicates the termination of string",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: It capitalizes only the first letter."
    },
    {
        "id": 39,
        "Question": "a) amil jones",
        "Options": [
            "b) What’s your first name? amil",
            "   My name is amil",
            "c) My name is lima",
            "d) My name is limA"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: It is used for modifying the variable."
    },
    {
        "id": 40,
        "Question": "a) amil jones",
        "Options": [
            "b) What’s your first name? amil",
            "   My name is Amil",
            "c) My name is lima",
            "d) My name is limA"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Capitalize method was not called at the time of last name, jones was not printed correctly it was not modified because ! was not used.\n\n\n\t\n\nOutput :\nWhat's your first name? amil\nWhat's your last name? jones\nMy name is Amil jones\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 41,
        "Question": "What do we mean by expression substitution?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Embedding the value of Ruby expression into a string using #{  }",
            "b) Substituting string functions",
            "c) Storing string value",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: “first_name.capitalize!” can not be in double quotes because it is a method.\n\n\nOutput:\nWhat's your first name? amil\nMy name is amil\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 42,
        "Question": "What does %{Learn ruby language} represents?",
        "Options": [
            "a) “Learn Ruby language”",
            "b) “%{Learn Ruby language}”",
            "c) ” Learn Ruby language ”",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The string is reversed  but it is not stored in any variable.\n\n\nOutput:\nWhat's your first name? amil\nMy name is amil\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 43,
        "Question": "What does %Q{ Learn ruby language } represents?",
        "Options": [
            "a) ” Learn Ruby language ”",
            "b) “%{ Learn Ruby language }”",
            "c) ” Learn Ruby language ”",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The string is reversed then and stored in a variable.\n\n\nOutput:\nwhat's your first name? amil\nMy name is limA\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 44,
        "Question": "What does %x!ls! represents?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Same as back tick command output `ls`",
            "b) Same as ‘x’",
            "c) Same as “xls”",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Strings are displayed #{} sequence."
    },
    {
        "id": 45,
        "Question": "Why do we use comments?",
        "Options": [
            "a) For later use to understand the working of the program",
            "b) It is an efficient way of programming",
            "c) It makes easy for the third person to understand",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: It is the efficient way of programming and easy to understand."
    },
    {
        "id": 46,
        "Question": "Which of the following type of comments are valid in ruby?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Single line comments",
            "b) Multi line comments",
            "c) Double line comments",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Double line comments comes under multiline comment."
    },
    {
        "id": 47,
        "Question": "How to comment multiple lines in ruby?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Using multiline comments",
            "b) Using single line comments",
            "c) No option to comment",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Multiple lines can be commented using multiline comments."
    },
    {
        "id": 48,
        "Question": "How to comment a single line?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Using #",
            "b) Using begin and end",
            "c) Using //",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Use # to comment single line."
    },
    {
        "id": 49,
        "Options": [
            "5. This the right way to comment a single line.",
            "   “Ruby”.length # I’m a single line comment!",
            "a) True",
            "b) False"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: We use # in a single line comment."
    },
    {
        "id": 50,
        "Question": "Why do we use =begin and =end?",
        "Options": [
            "a) To mark the start and end of multiline comment",
            "b) To comment multiple lines",
            "c) To avoid the use of # again and again",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: It finds the length of string."
    },
    {
        "id": 51,
        "Question": "10. What is the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"st0\">\"Ruby Language\"</span>.<span class=\"me1\">length</span>\n       <span class=\"coMULTI\">=begin\n       calculate length\n       =end</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 13",
            "b) 13 calculate length",
            "c) 12",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: We use =begin and =end to mark the beginning and end of the comment."
    },
    {
        "id": 52,
        "Question": "11. What is the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"st0\">\"Ruby Language\"</span>.<span class=\"me1\">length</span>\n       = <span class=\"kw1\">begin</span>\n       calculate length\n       = <span class=\"kw1\">end</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 13",
            "b) 12",
            "c) Error",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: No space should be given between = and begin and = or end."
    },
    {
        "id": 53,
        "Question": "What error does the if condition gives if not terminated with end statement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Syntax error",
            "b) Unexpected end",
            "c) Expecting keyword end",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The condition is true then only the code inside will execute."
    },
    {
        "id": 54,
        "Question": "4. What is the output of the following?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">if</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span>\n   <span class=\"kw3\">print</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"one is less than two\"</span>\n   <span class=\"kw1\">end</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) One is less than two",
            "b) Syntax error",
            "c) 1<2",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The condition must be true then if statement works."
    },
    {
        "id": 55,
        "Question": "5. What is the output of the code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\"> <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> <span class=\"nu0\">11</span><span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span>\n   <span class=\"kw3\">print</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"Eleven is less than two\"</span>\n   <span class=\"kw1\">end</span>\n   <span class=\"kw3\">print</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"11 is greater\"</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 11 is greater",
            "b) Eleven is less than two",
            "c) Eleven is less than two 11 is greater",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: We will get all the three errors."
    },
    {
        "id": 56,
        "Question": "a) Eleven is greater than two",
        "Options": [
            "b) You’r right",
            "c) Eleven is greater than two",
            "   You’r right",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The condition given in the if statement is not true hence it comes out of the if block.\n\n\nOutput:\n11 is greater\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 57,
        "Question": "a) True",
        "Options": [
            "b) Error",
            "c) True,error",
            "d) TRUE",
            "   Undefined method `Upcase’ for String"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: If condition is true then code is executed and then it comes out and then execute the remaining code.\n\n\nOutput:\nEleven is greater than two\nYou'r right\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 58,
        "Question": "10. What is the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\">x=<span class=\"nu0\">1</span>\n    <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">puts</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"x is greater than 2\"</span>\n    <span class=\"kw1\">elsif</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span>= <span class=\"nu0\">2</span> <span class=\"kw1\">and</span> x!=<span class=\"nu0\">0</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">puts</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"x is 1\"</span>\n    <span class=\"kw1\">else</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">puts</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"I can't guess the number\"</span>\n    <span class=\"kw1\">end</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) x is greater than 2",
            "b) x is 1",
            "c) I can’t guess the number",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The given condition is true so print statement gets executed.\n\n\n\t\n\nOutput:\nOne is less than two\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 59,
        "Question": "What is the use of else statement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) When the if condition is false then the next else condition will get executed",
            "b) When the if condition is false then the elsif condition will get executed",
            "c) When the if condition is false and if else condition is true then only it will get executed",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: When the if expression gives false value and the else condition is true then only it will get executed."
    },
    {
        "id": 60,
        "Question": "3. What is the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">if</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span>\n   <span class=\"kw3\">puts</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"false\"</span>\n   <span class=\"kw1\">else</span>\n   <span class=\"kw3\">puts</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"True\"</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) False",
            "b) True",
            "c) Syntax error",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: All the three statements execute only when it’s true."
    },
    {
        "id": 61,
        "Question": "4. What is the output of the code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\"> <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span>\n   <span class=\"kw3\">puts</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"false\"</span>\n   <span class=\"kw1\">end</span>\n   <span class=\"kw1\">else</span>\n   <span class=\"kw3\">puts</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"True\"</span>\n   <span class=\"kw1\">end</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) False",
            "b) True",
            "c) Syntax error",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: End statement is always must after the completion of else statement.\n\n\n\t\n\nOutput:\nSyntax error\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 62,
        "Question": "5. What is the output of the code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\">variable=<span class=\"kw2\">true</span>\n   <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> variable\n   <span class=\"kw3\">puts</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"true\"</span>\n   <span class=\"kw1\">else</span>\n   <span class=\"kw3\">puts</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"false\"</span>\n   <span class=\"kw1\">end</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) False",
            "b) True",
            "c) Syntax error",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: No two end statements required after if and else just one end statement is sufficient.\n\n\nOutput:\nSyntax error\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 63,
        "Question": "6. What is the output of the code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\"> variable=<span class=\"st0\">\"true\"</span>.<span class=\"me1\">reverse</span>\n   <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> variable\n   <span class=\"kw3\">puts</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"true\"</span>\n   <span class=\"kw1\">else</span>\n   <span class=\"kw3\">puts</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"false\"</span>\n   <span class=\"kw1\">end</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) False",
            "b) True",
            "c) Syntax error",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The condition is satisfied hence the if block code is executed.\n\n\nOutput:\nTrue\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 64,
        "Question": "7. What is the output of the code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\">variable=<span class=\"kw2\">true</span>\n   <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> !variable\n   <span class=\"kw3\">puts</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"true\"</span>\n   <span class=\"kw1\">else</span>\n   <span class=\"kw3\">puts</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"false\"</span>\n   <span class=\"kw1\">end</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) False",
            "b) True",
            "c) Syntax error",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Condition is satisfied and value is not changed.\n\n\nOutput:\nTrue\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 65,
        "Question": "8. What is the output of the code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\">variable=<span class=\"st0\">\"true\"</span>.<span class=\"me1\">length</span>\n   <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> variable\n   <span class=\"kw3\">puts</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"true\"</span>\n   <span class=\"kw1\">else</span>\n   <span class=\"kw3\">puts</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"false\"</span>\n   <span class=\"kw1\">end</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) False",
            "b) True",
            "c) Syntax error",
            "d) 4"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Condition is not satisfied so else part is executed.\n\n\nOutput:\nFalse\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 66,
        "Question": "Which of the following is valid conditional statement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) else",
            "b) els",
            "c) if else",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Condition is satisfied, and it is not effected by length method.\n\n\nOutput:\nTrue\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 67,
        "Question": "a) 1, 2",
        "Options": [
            "b) 1,2,3,4,5",
            "c) 1 2 1",
            "d) 1",
            "   2"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Value of counter is printed and then incremented.\n\n\nOutput:\n1\n2\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 68,
        "Question": "a) Undefined local variable counter",
        "Options": [
            "b) 1,2,3,4,5",
            "c) 1 2 1",
            "d) 1",
            "   2"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Counter value must not be commented.\n\n\nOutput:\nUndefined local variable counter\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 69,
        "Question": "Which of the following is valid conditional statement in Ruby?",
        "Options": [
            "a) elseif",
            "b) elsif",
            "c) else if",
            "d) elseiff"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: We use elsif conditional statement in Ruby."
    },
    {
        "id": 70,
        "Question": "6. What is the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\"> <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> !<span class=\"kw2\">true</span>\n   <span class=\"kw3\">print</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"False\"</span>\n   <span class=\"kw1\">elsif</span> !<span class=\"kw2\">true</span> <span class=\"sy0\">||</span> <span class=\"kw2\">true</span>\n   <span class=\"kw3\">print</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"True\"</span>\n   <span class=\"kw1\">end</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) True",
            "b) False",
            "c) Syntax eroor",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The syntax of elsif conditional statement is elsif with an expression."
    },
    {
        "id": 71,
        "Question": "7. What is the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\">variable = <span class=\"kw2\">false</span>\n   <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> variable\n   <span class=\"kw3\">print</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"false\"</span>\n   <span class=\"kw1\">elsif</span> !variable\n   <span class=\"kw3\">print</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"true\"</span> \n   <span class=\"kw1\">end</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) False",
            "b) True",
            "c) Syntax error",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: We can add many conditions between if/else statements using elsif conditional statement."
    },
    {
        "id": 72,
        "Question": "8. What is the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\">x=<span class=\"nu0\">7</span>\n   y=<span class=\"nu0\">9</span>\n   <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> x==y\n   <span class=\"kw3\">print</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"equal\"</span>\n   <span class=\"kw1\">elsif</span> x<span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span>y\n   <span class=\"kw3\">print</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"greater\"</span> \n   <span class=\"kw1\">else</span>\n   <span class=\"kw3\">print</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"less\"</span>\n   <span class=\"kw1\">end</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) equal",
            "b) greater",
            "c) less",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The counter value is 6 hence elsif part will get executed.\n\n\n        \n\nOutput:\n6\n12\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 73,
        "Question": "9. What is the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\">a=<span class=\"kw2\">true</span>\n   b=<span class=\"kw2\">false</span>\n   <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> a <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;&amp;</span> b\n   <span class=\"kw3\">puts</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"False\"</span>\n   <span class=\"kw1\">elsif</span> a <span class=\"sy0\">||</span> b\n   <span class=\"kw3\">puts</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"True\"</span>\n   <span class=\"kw1\">else</span>\n   <span class=\"kw3\">puts</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"neither true nor false\"</span>\n   <span class=\"kw1\">end</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) false",
            "b) true",
            "c) neither true nor false",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation:  As the counter value is negative the if condition is true hence the if block is executed.\n\n\n\t\n\nOutput:\n-3\n-2\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 74,
        "Question": "10. What is the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\">a=<span class=\"nu0\">10</span>\n    b=<span class=\"nu0\">2</span>\n    <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> a<span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span>b\n    a=a<span class=\"sy0\">*</span>b\n    <span class=\"kw3\">puts</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>a<span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n    <span class=\"kw1\">elsif</span> a<span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span>b\n    a=a<span class=\"sy0\">*</span>a<span class=\"sy0\">+</span>b\n    <span class=\"kw3\">puts</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>a<span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n    <span class=\"kw1\">else</span>\n    a=a<span class=\"sy0\">-</span>b\n    <span class=\"kw3\">puts</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>a<span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n    <span class=\"kw1\">end</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 20",
            "b) 102",
            "c) -98",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: !true || true evaluates to true, hence elsif block gets executed.\n\n\nOutput:\nTrue\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 75,
        "Question": "2. What is the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\">x=<span class=\"nu0\">3</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">unless</span> x<span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span>\n<span class=\"kw3\">puts</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"x is less than 2\"</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">else</span>\n<span class=\"kw3\">puts</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"x is greater than 2\"</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">end</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) x is greater than 2",
            "b) x is less than 2",
            "c) 3",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Executes code if condition is false. If the condition is true, code specified in the else clause is executed."
    },
    {
        "id": 76,
        "Question": "4. What is the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\">hungry=<span class=\"kw2\">false</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">unless</span> hungry\n <span class=\"kw3\">print</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"Not hungry\"</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">else</span>\n <span class=\"kw3\">print</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"Hungry\"</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">end</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Not hungry",
            "b) Hungry",
            "c) Syntax error",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The unless conditional statement is true so the unless clause is not executed.\n\n\n        \n\nOutput: \nx is greater than 2\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 77,
        "Question": "6. What is the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\">counter=<span class=\"nu0\">12</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">unless</span> counter\n <span class=\"kw3\">print</span> counter<span class=\"sy0\">+</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">else</span>\n <span class=\"kw3\">print</span> counter<span class=\"sy0\">+</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">end</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 13",
            "b) 14",
            "c) 15",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: if condition is evaluated to true so it is executed and the second unless condition is evaluated to false so it is also executed.\n\n\n\t\n\nOutput:\n   1--Value is set\n   3--Value is set\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 78,
        "Question": "7. What is the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">unless</span> <span class=\"kw2\">true</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;&amp;</span> <span class=\"kw2\">false</span>\n<span class=\"kw3\">print</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"false\"</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">else</span> \n    <span class=\"kw3\">print</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"ruby\"</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">end</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) True",
            "b) False",
            "c) Nil",
            "d) Syntax error"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: As hungry is initialized to false hence the unless condition is executed.\n\n\nOutput:\nNot hungry\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 79,
        "Question": "8. What is the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw3\">print</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"2 is less than 3\"</span> <span class=\"kw1\">unless</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span><span class=\"nu0\">3</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 2>3",
            "b) 2 is less than 3",
            "c) Syntax error",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The unless condition must be false in order to execute the code."
    },
    {
        "id": 80,
        "Question": "a) x is less than y",
        "Options": [
            "b) x is less than y+1",
            "c) x is less than y",
            "   x is less than y+1",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Counter is assigned the value 1, so the unless conditional statement is true and hence it is not executed.\n\n\nOutput:\n14\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 81,
        "Question": "a) x is less than y",
        "Options": [
            "b) x is less than y+1",
            "c) x is less than y",
            "   x is less than y+1",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: true && false will evaluate to false so unless block will get executed.\n\n\nOutput:\nfalse\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 82,
        "Question": "1. What is the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\">age =  <span class=\"nu0\">5</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">case</span> age\n<span class=\"kw1\">when</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span> .. <span class=\"nu0\">2</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">puts</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"baby\"</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">when</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span> .. <span class=\"nu0\">6</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">puts</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"little child\"</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">when</span> <span class=\"nu0\">7</span> .. <span class=\"nu0\">12</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">puts</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"child\"</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">when</span> <span class=\"nu0\">13</span> .. <span class=\"nu0\">18</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">puts</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"youth\"</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">else</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">puts</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"adult\"</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">end</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) baby",
            "b) adult",
            "c) little child",
            "d) youth"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The age is already assigned the value 5 and so the case statement will check in which range does 5 lies and execute it.\n\n\n\t\n\n        \n\nOutput:\nlittle child\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 83,
        "Question": "3. What is the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\">age =  <span class=\"nu0\">4</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">case</span> age\n<span class=\"kw3\">puts</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"baby\"</span> <span class=\"kw1\">when</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span> .. <span class=\"nu0\">2</span>\n<span class=\"kw3\">puts</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"little child\"</span> <span class=\"kw1\">when</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span> .. <span class=\"nu0\">6</span>\n<span class=\"kw3\">puts</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"child\"</span> <span class=\"kw1\">when</span> <span class=\"nu0\">7</span> .. <span class=\"nu0\">12</span>\n<span class=\"kw3\">puts</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"youth\"</span> <span class=\"kw1\">when</span> <span class=\"nu0\">13</span> .. <span class=\"nu0\">18</span>\n<span class=\"kw3\">puts</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"adult\"</span> <span class=\"kw1\">else</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">end</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) adult",
            "b) youth",
            "c) child",
            "d) syntax error"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The following syntax is used for ruby case statement."
    },
    {
        "id": 84,
        "Question": "a) alphabet a",
        "Options": [
            "b) b",
            "   alphabet b",
            "c) alphabet c",
            "d) Syntax error"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer:c\nExplanation: The for loop will keep on incrementing from 1 to 5 and then prints the value in particular case statements.\n\n\nOutput:\n1\nbaby\n2\nbaby\n3\nlittle child\n4\nlittle child\n5\nlittle child\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 85,
        "Question": "9. What is the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\">l=<span class=\"nu0\">9</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">case</span> l\n<span class=\"kw3\">print</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"ruby\"</span> <span class=\"kw1\">when</span> l==<span class=\"nu0\">9</span>\n<span class=\"kw3\">print</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"language\"</span> <span class=\"kw1\">when</span> l==<span class=\"nu0\">10</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">end</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) l==9",
            "b) l==10",
            "c) Syntax error",
            "d) Ruby"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: After taking input from the user will check which string is entered and goes to particular case statement.\n\n\nOutput:\nb\nalphabet b\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 86,
        "Question": "3. What will the following code evaluate to?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\">a=<span class=\"nu0\">9</span>!=<span class=\"nu0\">10</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) True",
            "b) False",
            "c) Syntax error",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The == is used to compare two things are equal or not and hence it is known as comparator/relational operator."
    },
    {
        "id": 87,
        "Question": "4. What is the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\">test_1 = <span class=\"nu0\">17</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">16</span>\n<span class=\"kw3\">puts</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>test_1<span class=\"br0\">)</span>\ntest_2 = <span class=\"nu0\">21</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span>= <span class=\"nu0\">30</span>\n<span class=\"kw3\">puts</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>test_2<span class=\"br0\">)</span>\ntest_3 = <span class=\"nu0\">9</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span>= <span class=\"nu0\">9</span>\n<span class=\"kw3\">puts</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>test_3<span class=\"br0\">)</span>\ntest_4 = <span class=\"sy0\">-</span><span class=\"nu0\">11</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">4</span>\n<span class=\"kw3\">puts</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>test_4<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) True false true false",
            "b) True True True False",
            "c) False False True True",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The ‘=’ is known as assignment operator."
    },
    {
        "id": 88,
        "Question": "5. What is the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\">a=<span class=\"st0\">\"string\"</span>\nb=<span class=\"st0\">\"strings\"</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">if</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>a==b<span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">print</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"a and b are same\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">else</span> \n    <span class=\"kw3\">print</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"Not same\"</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">end</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) a and b are same",
            "b) Not same",
            "c) a==b",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: 9 is not equal to 10 hence it will evaluate to true.\n\n\n        \n\nOutput:\nTrue\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 89,
        "Question": "7. What is the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\">a=<span class=\"nu0\">10</span>\nb=<span class=\"nu0\">9</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">if</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>a<span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span>b<span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">print</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"a greater than b\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">else</span> \n    <span class=\"kw3\">print</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"Not greater\"</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">end</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) a greater than b",
            "b) Not greater",
            "c) Syntax error",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: All the expressions which are correct will evluate to true rest all will evaluate to false.\n\n\n\t\n\nOutput:\ntrue\ntrue\ntrue\nfalse\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 90,
        "Question": "Which of the following are used for comparison?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Equal to",
            "b) Not equal to",
            "c) Less than or greater than",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: a and b are not similar hence the else condition will get executed.\n\n\nOutput:\nNot same\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 91,
        "Question": "9. What is the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">if</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>a==<span class=\"nu0\">10</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;&amp;</span> b=<span class=\"nu0\">9</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">print</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"true\"</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">else</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">print</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"false\"</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">end</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) True",
            "b) False",
            "c) Error",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Assignment operator is used for assigning a value."
    },
    {
        "id": 92,
        "Question": "10. What is the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\">counter=<span class=\"nu0\">1</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">if</span> counter<span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span>=<span class=\"nu0\">5</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">puts</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>counter<span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n    counter=counter<span class=\"sy0\">+</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Syntax error",
            "b) 1 2",
            "c) 1",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Assigning the value to the variable and checking the condition.\n\n\nOutput:\na greater than b\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 93,
        "Question": "Which of the following is a valid boolean operator?",
        "Options": [
            "a) and(&&)",
            "b) or(||)",
            "c) not(!)",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Boolean operators result in boolean values like true or false."
    },
    {
        "id": 94,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\">boolean_1 = <span class=\"nu0\">77</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">78</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;&amp;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">77</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">77</span>\n<span class=\"kw3\">puts</span> boolean_1</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) True",
            "b) False",
            "c) Error",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: We have three boolean operators which are and, or, not."
    },
    {
        "id": 95,
        "Question": "9. What will be the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\"> boolean_1 = <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">3</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">4</span> <span class=\"sy0\">||</span> <span class=\"kw2\">false</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;&amp;</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw2\">false</span> <span class=\"sy0\">||</span> <span class=\"kw2\">true</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"kw3\">puts</span> boolean_1</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) True",
            "b) False",
            "c) Error",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The && operator only results in true when both the values are true rest all cases it evaluates to false."
    },
    {
        "id": 96,
        "Question": "10. What will be the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\"> boolean_1 = !<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">3</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">4</span> <span class=\"sy0\">||</span> <span class=\"kw2\">false</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;&amp;</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw2\">false</span> <span class=\"sy0\">||</span> <span class=\"kw2\">true</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"kw3\">puts</span> boolean_1</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) True",
            "b) False",
            "c) Error",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Boolean operator && evaluates to true only when both the values are true."
    },
    {
        "id": 97,
        "Question": "11. What will be the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\"> boolean_1 = <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">**</span><span class=\"nu0\">3</span> != <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">**</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span> <span class=\"sy0\">||</span> <span class=\"kw2\">true</span>\n<span class=\"kw3\">puts</span> boolean_1</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) True",
            "b) False",
            "c) Error",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: 77<78 is true but 77<77 is false hence the overall expression will evaluate to false.\n\n\n\n\n\t\n\nOutput:\nFalse\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 98,
        "Question": "12. What will be the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\"> boolean_1 = <span class=\"kw2\">false</span> <span class=\"sy0\">||</span> <span class=\"sy0\">-</span><span class=\"nu0\">10</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> <span class=\"sy0\">-</span><span class=\"nu0\">9</span>\n<span class=\"kw3\">puts</span> boolean_1</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) True",
            "b) False",
            "c) Error",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Boolean operator || evaluates to true only when both the values are true or one is true and other is false."
    },
    {
        "id": 99,
        "Question": "13. What will be the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\"> boolean_1 = !<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">700</span> <span class=\"sy0\">/</span> <span class=\"nu0\">10</span> == <span class=\"nu0\">70</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"kw3\">puts</span> boolean_1</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) True",
            "b) False",
            "c) Error",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Boolean operator && evaluates to true only when both the values are true and !true means false hence the whole expression will evaluate to false."
    },
    {
        "id": 100,
        "Question": "14. What will be the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\"> boolean_1 = !<span class=\"kw2\">true</span>\n<span class=\"kw3\">puts</span> boolean_1  \nboolean_2 = !<span class=\"kw2\">true</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;&amp;</span> !<span class=\"kw2\">true</span>\n<span class=\"kw3\">puts</span> boolean_2</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) True True",
            "b) False False",
            "c) True False",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Boolean operator && evaluates to true only when both the values are true."
    },
    {
        "id": 101,
        "Question": "15. What will be the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\"> boolean_2 = !<span class=\"kw2\">true</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;&amp;</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>!<span class=\"kw2\">true</span> <span class=\"sy0\">||</span> <span class=\"nu0\">100</span> != <span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"sy0\">**</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"kw3\">puts</span> boolean_2</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) True",
            "b) False",
            "c) Error",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: 3<4 is true and true or false will evaluate to true hence the overall expression will evaluate to true.\n\n\n\n\nOutput:\nTrue\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 102,
        "Question": "Which of the following is a valid assignment operator?",
        "Options": [
            "a) +=",
            "b) -=",
            "c) *=",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Assignment operators are +=, -=, *=, /=, **=."
    },
    {
        "id": 103,
        "Question": "What does the **= assignment operator do?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Multiplies the value twice",
            "b) It is used as exponent like 2**3=8",
            "c) It is the multiplication operator.",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: a**=2 means a to the power of two.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 104,
        "Question": "3. What is the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\">counter = <span class=\"nu0\">2</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">while</span> counter <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">68</span>\n  <span class=\"kw3\">puts</span> counter\n  counter<span class=\"sy0\">**</span>=<span class=\"nu0\">2</span>\n  <span class=\"kw1\">end</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 2 4 16 64",
            "b) 2 4 16",
            "c) 2 4 16 256",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The counter will increment by the power of two.\n\n\n        \n\nOutput:\n2\n4\n16\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 105,
        "Question": "4. What is the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\">counter = <span class=\"nu0\">1</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">while</span> counter <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">11</span>\n  <span class=\"kw3\">puts</span> counter\n  counter<span class=\"sy0\">+</span>=<span class=\"nu0\">1</span>\n  <span class=\"kw1\">end</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1 2 3 4 5",
            "b) 1…10",
            "c) 1..10",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: 1..10 inclusive 10 also. The counter will increment by one.\n\n\n\t\n\nOutput:\n1\n2\n3\n4\n5\n6\n7\n8\n9\n10\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 106,
        "Question": "6. What is the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\">counter = <span class=\"nu0\">100</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">while</span> counter <span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span>\n  <span class=\"kw3\">puts</span> counter\n  counter<span class=\"sy0\">/</span>=<span class=\"nu0\">5</span>\n  <span class=\"kw1\">end</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 100 20 4",
            "b) 100 20 5",
            "c) 100..5",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Ruby does not support ++ or — operator. It only supports += or -= operator.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 107,
        "Question": "7. What is the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\">counter = <span class=\"nu0\">100</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">while</span> counter <span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span>\n  <span class=\"kw3\">puts</span> counter\n  counter<span class=\"sy0\">-</span>=<span class=\"nu0\">25</span>\n  <span class=\"kw1\">end</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 100 75 50 25",
            "b) 100 25 5",
            "c) 100..5",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: First counter will be 100 then after division it will become 20 then again it will become 4 and then it will come out of the loop.\n\n\nOutput: \n100\n20\n4\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 108,
        "Question": "8. What is the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\">counter = <span class=\"sy0\">-</span><span class=\"nu0\">50</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">while</span> counter <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span><span class=\"nu0\">0</span>\n  <span class=\"kw3\">puts</span> counter\n  counter<span class=\"sy0\">+</span>=<span class=\"nu0\">10</span>\n  <span class=\"kw1\">end</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 100 75 50 25",
            "b) -50 -40 -30 -20 -10",
            "c) 100..5",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The counter value will decrement by 25.\n\n\nOutput: \n100\n75\n50\n25\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 109,
        "Question": "10. What is the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\">a = <span class=\"nu0\">22.5</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">while</span> a <span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span><span class=\"nu0\">11.5</span>\n  <span class=\"kw3\">puts</span> a\n  a<span class=\"sy0\">-</span>=<span class=\"nu0\">3.5</span>\n  <span class=\"kw1\">end</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 22.5 19.0 15.5 12.0",
            "b) 22.5 11.5",
            "c) 100..5",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The counter value will decrement by 10 till the counter value reaches zero.\n\n\nOutput: \n-50\n-40\n-30\n-20\n-10\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 110,
        "Question": "11. What is the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\">a = <span class=\"nu0\">5</span>\nb=<span class=\"nu0\">10</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">while</span> a <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span><span class=\"nu0\">10</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;&amp;</span> b<span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span><span class=\"nu0\">20</span>\n  <span class=\"kw3\">puts</span> a<span class=\"sy0\">+</span>b\n  a<span class=\"sy0\">+</span>=<span class=\"nu0\">2</span>\n  b<span class=\"sy0\">+</span>=<span class=\"nu0\">2</span>\n  <span class=\"kw1\">end</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 10 20",
            "b) 15 19 23",
            "c) 15 16 17 18 19 20",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Both the expression increments the value by 1."
    },
    {
        "id": 111,
        "Question": "12. What is the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\">a = <span class=\"nu0\">5</span>\nb=<span class=\"nu0\">10</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">while</span> a <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span><span class=\"nu0\">10</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;&amp;</span> b<span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span><span class=\"nu0\">20</span>\n  <span class=\"kw3\">puts</span> a<span class=\"sy0\">*</span>b\n  a<span class=\"sy0\">+</span>=<span class=\"nu0\">2</span>\n  b<span class=\"sy0\">+</span>=<span class=\"nu0\">2</span>\n  <span class=\"kw1\">end</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 10 20",
            "b) 15 19 23",
            "c) 50 84 126",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The counter value will decrement by 3.5 till the counter value reaches 11.5.\n\n\nOutput: \n22.5\n19.0\n15.5\n12.0\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 112,
        "Question": "13.  What is the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\"> a= <span class=\"nu0\">5</span>\nb=<span class=\"nu0\">10</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">while</span> a <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span><span class=\"nu0\">10</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;&amp;</span> b<span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span><span class=\"nu0\">20</span>\n  <span class=\"kw3\">puts</span> a<span class=\"sy0\">-</span>b\n  a<span class=\"sy0\">+</span>=<span class=\"nu0\">2</span>\n  b<span class=\"sy0\">+</span>=<span class=\"nu0\">2</span>\n  <span class=\"kw1\">end</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 10 20",
            "b) 15 19 23",
            "c) -5 -5 -5",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The counter value will increment by two till a<10 and b<20.\n\n\n\n\nOutput: \n15 \n19 \n23\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 113,
        "Question": "14. What is the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\"> a = <span class=\"nu0\">5</span>\nb=<span class=\"nu0\">10</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">while</span> a <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span><span class=\"nu0\">10</span> <span class=\"sy0\">||</span> b<span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span><span class=\"nu0\">20</span>\n  <span class=\"kw3\">puts</span> a<span class=\"sy0\">*</span>b\n  a<span class=\"sy0\">+</span>=<span class=\"nu0\">2</span>\n  b<span class=\"sy0\">+</span>=<span class=\"nu0\">2</span>\n  <span class=\"kw1\">end</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 10 20",
            "b) 50 84 126 176 234",
            "c) -5 -5 -5",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The counter value will increment by two till a<10 and b<20 and multiply a and b.\n\n\n\n\nOutput: \n50\n84\n126\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 114,
        "Question": "15. What is the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\"> a = <span class=\"nu0\">5</span>\nb=<span class=\"nu0\">10</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">while</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>a <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span><span class=\"nu0\">10</span> <span class=\"sy0\">||</span> b<span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span><span class=\"nu0\">20</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">&amp;&amp;</span><span class=\"kw2\">true</span>\n  <span class=\"kw3\">puts</span> a<span class=\"sy0\">*</span>b\n  a<span class=\"sy0\">+</span>=<span class=\"nu0\">2</span>\n  b<span class=\"sy0\">+</span>=<span class=\"nu0\">2</span>\n  <span class=\"kw1\">end</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 10 20",
            "b) 50 84 126 176 234",
            "c) -5 -5 -5",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Even if both the values are incremented by two the difference remains the same.\n\n\nOutput: \n-5\n-5\n-5\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 115,
        "Question": "2. What is the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\">counter = <span class=\"nu0\">1</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">while</span> counter <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">11</span>\n  <span class=\"kw3\">puts</span> counter\n  counter = counter <span class=\"sy0\">+</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">end</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Prints the number from 1 to 10",
            "b) Prints the number from 1 to 11",
            "c) Prints the number from 2 to 10",
            "d) Infinite loop"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: While condition is true keep on looping.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 116,
        "Question": "3. What is the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\">counter = <span class=\"kw2\">true</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">while</span> counter !=<span class=\"kw2\">false</span>\n  <span class=\"kw3\">puts</span> counter\n<span class=\"kw1\">end</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) True",
            "b) False",
            "c) Syntax error",
            "d) Infinite loop"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Counter value is initialized to 1 and it keeps on looping till the counter is less than 11.\n\n\n\t\n\n        \n\nOutput:\n1\n2\n3\n4\n5\n6\n7\n8\n9\n10\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 117,
        "Question": "4. What is the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\">i = <span class=\"nu0\">0</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">while</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span>\n  <span class=\"kw3\">puts</span> i\n   i=<span class=\"br0\">(</span>i<span class=\"sy0\">+</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">**</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">end</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1 2 3 4 5",
            "b) 0 1 4",
            "c) 0 1",
            "d) 1 4"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Counter value is true in all cases hence true will be printed infinite times.\n\n\n\t\n\nOutput:\ntrue\ntrue\n...Infinite loop\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 118,
        "Question": "5. What is the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\">a=<span class=\"nu0\">5</span>\nb=<span class=\"nu0\">15</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">while</span> a<span class=\"sy0\">&amp;&amp;</span>b\n<span class=\"kw3\">puts</span> a<span class=\"sy0\">+</span>b\n<span class=\"kw1\">end</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 5..15",
            "b) 20",
            "c) Infinite loop",
            "d) 5 15"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: (i+1)**2 means i+1 to the power of 2 and hence the loop continues till i<5.\n\n\n\n\nOutput:\n0\n1\n4\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 119,
        "Question": "6. What is the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\">a=<span class=\"nu0\">5</span>\nb=<span class=\"nu0\">15</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">while</span> b<span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span>a\n<span class=\"kw3\">puts</span> a<span class=\"sy0\">*</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>b<span class=\"sy0\">-</span>a<span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">while</span> a<span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span>b\n  a<span class=\"sy0\">+</span>=<span class=\"nu0\">1</span>\n  b<span class=\"sy0\">-</span>=<span class=\"nu0\">1</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">end</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">end</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 5..15",
            "b) 50",
            "c) Infinite loop",
            "d) 5 50"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: a && b will always be true so the looping will never come to an end.\n\n\nOutput:\n20\n20\n....infinite loop\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 120,
        "Question": "7. What is the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\">i = <span class=\"nu0\">3</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">while</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span> <span class=\"kw1\">do</span>\n  <span class=\"kw3\">print</span> i\n  i <span class=\"sy0\">-</span>= <span class=\"nu0\">1</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">end</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 3",
            "b) 321",
            "c) Infinite loop",
            "d) 3 2 1 0"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: b>a will always be true so the looping will never come to an end and as a>b will always be false it will never enter the other while loop.\n\n\nOutput:\n50\n50\n....infinite loop\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 121,
        "Question": "8. What is the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\">i = <span class=\"nu0\">50</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">while</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">25</span> <span class=\"kw1\">do</span>\n  <span class=\"kw3\">print</span> <span class=\"nu0\">50</span><span class=\"sy0\">/</span>i\n  i <span class=\"sy0\">-</span>= <span class=\"nu0\">1</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">end</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 50..25",
            "b) 50..1",
            "c) Infinite loop",
            "d) 1111111111111111111111111"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The do statement here indicates that till the while condition is true execute the instructions.\n\n\nOutput:\n321\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 122,
        "Question": "9. What is the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\">a = <span class=\"nu0\">5</span>\nb=<span class=\"nu0\">10</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">while</span> a<span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span>b <span class=\"kw1\">do</span>\n  <span class=\"kw3\">puts</span> a<span class=\"sy0\">*</span>b\n  a<span class=\"sy0\">+</span>=<span class=\"nu0\">2</span>\n  b<span class=\"sy0\">-</span>=<span class=\"nu0\">2</span>\n  <span class=\"kw1\">end</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 5 10",
            "b) 50 56",
            "c) Infinite loop",
            "d) 5 6 7 8 9 10"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The do statement here indicates that till the while condition is true execute the instructions, so here it will print all the integer values of (50/i) which\nwill always be one.\n\n\nOutput:\n1111111111111111111111111\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 123,
        "Question": "2. What is the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\">counter = <span class=\"nu0\">1</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">until</span> counter <span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">10</span>\n  <span class=\"kw3\">puts</span> counter\ncounter<span class=\"sy0\">+</span>=<span class=\"nu0\">1</span> \n  <span class=\"kw1\">end</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10",
            "b) 11 12 13 14 … infinite loop",
            "c) 0 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The until loop is sort of like backward while.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 124,
        "Question": "3. What is the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\">counter = <span class=\"nu0\">0</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">until</span> counter <span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span>= <span class=\"nu0\">10</span>\n  <span class=\"kw3\">puts</span> counter\ncounter<span class=\"sy0\">+</span>=<span class=\"nu0\">1</span> \n  <span class=\"kw1\">end</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10",
            "b) 11 12 13 14 … infinite loop",
            "c) 0 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Until the condition is false continue looping.\n\n\n\t\n\n        \n\nOutput:\n1\n2\n3\n4\n5\n6\n7\n8\n9\n10\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 125,
        "Question": "4. What is the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\">i = <span class=\"nu0\">3</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">while</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span> <span class=\"kw1\">do</span>\n  <span class=\"kw3\">puts</span> i\n  i <span class=\"sy0\">-</span>= <span class=\"nu0\">1</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">end</span>\n&nbsp;\nj = <span class=\"nu0\">3</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">until</span> j == <span class=\"nu0\">0</span> <span class=\"kw1\">do</span>\n  <span class=\"kw3\">puts</span> j\n  j <span class=\"sy0\">-</span>= <span class=\"nu0\">1</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">end</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1 2 3 1 2 3",
            "b) 3 2 1 3 2 1",
            "c) 0 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Until the condition is false continue looping and here 10 will not be included because condition becomes true when counter is 10.\n\n\n\t\n\nOutput:\n0\n1\n2\n3\n4\n5\n6\n7\n8\n9\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 126,
        "Question": "5. What is the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\">a=<span class=\"st0\">\"hungry\"</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">until</span> !a\n<span class=\"kw3\">puts</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"hungry\"</span>\na=!a\n<span class=\"kw1\">end</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) hungry",
            "b) Nil",
            "c) Error",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: When it comes out of the while loop the until loop starts executing.\n\n\nOutput:\n3\n2\n1\n3\n2\n1\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 127,
        "Question": "6. What is the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\">m= <span class=\"nu0\">8</span>\n<span class=\"kw3\">loop</span> <span class=\"kw1\">do</span>\n    m <span class=\"sy0\">+</span>= <span class=\"nu0\">2</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">puts</span> m\n    <span class=\"kw1\">break</span> <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> m == <span class=\"nu0\">16</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">end</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 10 12 14 16",
            "b) Nil",
            "c) Error",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Until the condition is not met execute the loop.\n\n\nOutput:\nhungry\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 128,
        "Question": "7. What is the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\">m=<span class=\"nu0\">0</span>\n<span class=\"kw3\">loop</span> <span class=\"kw1\">do</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">print</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"ruby\"</span>\n    m<span class=\"sy0\">+</span>=<span class=\"nu0\">1</span>\n    <span class=\"kw1\">break</span> <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> m==<span class=\"nu0\">5</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">end</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) rubyrubyrubyrubyrubyruby",
            "b) rubyrubyrubyrubyruby",
            "c) Error",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Execute the loop till the condition is met.\n\n\nOutput:\n10\n12\n14\n16\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 129,
        "Question": "8. What is the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\">m=<span class=\"nu0\">0</span>\n<span class=\"kw3\">loop</span> <span class=\"kw1\">do</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">puts</span> m<span class=\"sy0\">*</span><span class=\"nu0\">10</span>\n    m<span class=\"sy0\">+</span>=<span class=\"nu0\">1</span>\n    <span class=\"kw1\">break</span> <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> m==<span class=\"nu0\">5</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">end</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0 10 20 30 40",
            "b) 10 20 30 40 50",
            "c) Error",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Execute the loop till m!=5 and then break when m=5.\n\n\nOutput:\nrubyrubyrubyrubyruby\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 130,
        "Question": "9. What is the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\">m=<span class=\"nu0\">0</span>\n<span class=\"kw3\">loop</span> <span class=\"kw1\">do</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">puts</span> <span class=\"nu0\">101</span>\n    m<span class=\"sy0\">+</span>=<span class=\"nu0\">1</span>\n    <span class=\"kw1\">break</span> <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> m==<span class=\"nu0\">5</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">end</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 101 101 101 101 101",
            "b) 10 20 30 40 50",
            "c) Error",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Execute the loop till m!=5 and then print m*10.\n\n\nOutput:\n0\n10\n20\n30\n40\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 131,
        "Question": "10. What is the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\">m=<span class=\"nu0\">5</span>\n<span class=\"kw3\">loop</span> <span class=\"kw1\">do</span>\n    m<span class=\"sy0\">-</span>=<span class=\"nu0\">1</span>\n    <span class=\"kw1\">break</span> <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> m==<span class=\"nu0\">0</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">end</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1 2 3 4 5",
            "b) 10 20 30 40 50",
            "c) Error",
            "d) Nil"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Execute the loop till m!=5 and then print 101 five times.\n\n\nOutput:\n101\n101\n101\n101\n101\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 132,
        "Question": "1. What is the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">for</span> num <span class=\"kw1\">in</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span>...<span class=\"nu0\">5</span>\n  <span class=\"kw3\">puts</span> num\n<span class=\"kw1\">end</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1 2 3 4 5",
            "b) 1 2 3 4",
            "c) 2 3 4 5",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: As the range i.e 1…10 is exclusive the loop will loop till 4 and then it will come out of the loop.\n\n\n\t\n\n        \n\nOutput:\n1\n2\n3\n4\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 133,
        "Question": "What does the 1…10 indicate?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Inclusive range",
            "b) Exclusive range",
            "c) Both inclusive and exclusive range",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: 1…10 means start from one and go till 9 and don’t include 10. "
    },
    {
        "id": 134,
        "Question": "3. What is the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">for</span> num <span class=\"kw1\">in</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span>..<span class=\"nu0\">3</span>\n  <span class=\"kw3\">puts</span> num\n  <span class=\"kw1\">for</span> i <span class=\"kw1\">in</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span>..<span class=\"nu0\">2</span>\n  <span class=\"kw3\">puts</span> num<span class=\"sy0\">*</span>i\n  <span class=\"kw1\">end</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">end</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1 2 3 4 5",
            "b) 1 1 2 2 2 4 3 3 6",
            "c) 2 3 4 5",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: This is a nested loop.\n\n\n\t\n\nOutput:\n1\n1\n2\n2\n2\n4\n3\n3\n6\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 135,
        "Question": "4. What is the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\">m= <span class=\"nu0\">0</span>\n<span class=\"kw3\">loop</span> <span class=\"kw1\">do</span>\n    m <span class=\"sy0\">+</span>= <span class=\"nu0\">1</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">print</span> m\n    <span class=\"kw1\">break</span> <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> m == <span class=\"nu0\">10</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">end</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 12345678910",
            "b) 1 2 3 4",
            "c) 2 3 4 5",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Loop till the condition is met and break when the condition is not satisfied.\n\n\nOutput:\n12345678910\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 136,
        "Question": "5. What is the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">for</span> num <span class=\"kw1\">in</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span>..<span class=\"nu0\">5</span>\n  <span class=\"kw3\">puts</span> num<span class=\"sy0\">*</span>num\n<span class=\"kw1\">end</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 12345678910",
            "b) 1 2 3 4",
            "c) 1 4 9 16 25",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Loop till the condition is met and break when the condition is not satisfied.\n\n\nOutput:\n1\n4\n9\n16\n25\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 137,
        "Question": "6. What is the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">for</span> num <span class=\"kw1\">in</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span>..<span class=\"nu0\">3</span>\n  <span class=\"kw3\">puts</span> num<span class=\"sy0\">*</span>num\n  m= <span class=\"nu0\">0</span>\n<span class=\"kw3\">loop</span> <span class=\"kw1\">do</span>\n    m <span class=\"sy0\">+</span>= <span class=\"nu0\">1</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">puts</span> m\n    <span class=\"kw1\">break</span> <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> m == <span class=\"nu0\">3</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">end</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">end</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 12345678910",
            "b) 1 1 2 3 4 1 2 3 9 1 2 3",
            "c) 1 4 9 16 25",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Loop till the condition is met and break when the condition is not satisfied.\n\n\nOutput:\n1\n1\n2\n3\n4\n1\n2\n3\n9\n1\n2\n3\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 138,
        "Question": "7. What is the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw3\">loop</span> <span class=\"kw1\">do</span>\n    m <span class=\"sy0\">+</span>= <span class=\"nu0\">1</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">puts</span> m\n    <span class=\"kw1\">break</span> <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> m == <span class=\"nu0\">3</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">end</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Garbage values",
            "b) 1 1 2 3 4 1 2 3 9 1 2 3",
            "c) 1 4 9 16 25",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Loop till the condition is met and break when the condition is not satisfied.\n\n\nOutput:\nGarbage values\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 139,
        "Question": "8. What is the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\">i=<span class=\"nu0\">1</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">for</span> i <span class=\"kw1\">in</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span>..<span class=\"nu0\">10</span>\n<span class=\"kw3\">puts</span> i^<span class=\"nu0\">2</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">end</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 7 4 5 10 11 8",
            "b) 25 36 49 64 81 100",
            "c) 1 4 9 16 25",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Initialize the value of i and then print i**2.\n\n\nOutput:\n25\n36\n49\n64\n81\n100\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 140,
        "Question": " What does the 1..10 indicate?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Inclusive range",
            "b) Exclusive range",
            "c) Both inclusive and exclusive range",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: 1..10 means start from one and go till 9 and even include 10. "
    },
    {
        "id": 141,
        "Question": "10. What is the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\">i=<span class=\"nu0\">5</span>\nj=<span class=\"nu0\">10</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">for</span> i <span class=\"kw1\">in</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span>..<span class=\"nu0\">10</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;&amp;</span> j <span class=\"kw1\">in</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span>..<span class=\"nu0\">10</span>\n<span class=\"kw3\">puts</span> i<span class=\"sy0\">**</span>j\n<span class=\"kw1\">end</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Syntax error",
            "b) 25 36 49 64 81 100",
            "c) 1 4 9 16 25",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Initialize the value of i  and j and then when condition is true print i**j.\n\n\nOutput:\nsyntax error, unexpected keyword_in, expecting keyword_do_cond or ';' or '\\n'\nfor i in 5..10 && j in 5..10 syntax error, unexpected keyword_end, expecting $end\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 142,
        "Question": "2. What will be output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\">my_array = <span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span>, <span class=\"nu0\">2</span>, <span class=\"nu0\">3</span>, <span class=\"nu0\">4</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span>\n<span class=\"kw3\">print</span> my_array</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) [1, 2, 3, 4].",
            "b) 1234",
            "c) Error",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: We can store multiple value in one single variable known as arrays.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 143,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw3\">array</span> = <span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">100</span>, <span class=\"nu0\">200</span>, <span class=\"nu0\">300</span>, <span class=\"nu0\">400</span>, <span class=\"nu0\">500</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span>\n<span class=\"kw3\">print</span> <span class=\"kw3\">array</span><span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">4</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 400",
            "b) 500",
            "c) Nil",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: A variable my_array is declared and [1, 2, 3, 4] is stored in that variable.\n\n\n\t\n\n        \n\nOutput:\n[1, 2, 3, 4]\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 144,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the following?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw3\">array</span> = <span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">100</span>, <span class=\"nu0\">200</span>, <span class=\"nu0\">300</span>, <span class=\"nu0\">400</span>, <span class=\"nu0\">500</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span>\n<span class=\"kw3\">print</span> <span class=\"kw3\">array</span><span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 400",
            "b) 500",
            "c) Nil",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Array’s starting index is index 0 not index 1."
    },
    {
        "id": 145,
        "Question": "6. What will be the output of the following?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw3\">array</span> = <span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">100</span>, <span class=\"nu0\">200</span>, <span class=\"nu0\">300</span>, <span class=\"nu0\">400</span>, <span class=\"nu0\">500</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span>\n<span class=\"kw3\">print</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"array[5]\"</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) array[5].",
            "b) 500",
            "c) Nil",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Array’s index start from 0 so array[4] will give 500.\n\n\n\t\n\nOutput:\n500\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 146,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\">array1 = <span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">100</span>, <span class=\"nu0\">200</span>, <span class=\"nu0\">300</span>, <span class=\"nu0\">400</span>, <span class=\"nu0\">500</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span>\narray2 = <span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">2</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">3</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">4</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">if</span> array1 == array2\n<span class=\"kw3\">print</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"They are equal\"</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">else</span> \n    <span class=\"kw3\">print</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"Not equal\"</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">end</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) They are equal",
            "b) Not equal",
            "c) Nil",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Array’s index start from 0 so array[5] will give nothing.\n\n\nOutput:\nNil\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 147,
        "Question": "8. What will be the output of the following?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\">array1 = <span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">0</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">0</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span>\narray2 = <span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">0</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">0</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">if</span> array1 == array2\n<span class=\"kw3\">print</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"They are equal\"</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">else</span> \n    <span class=\"kw3\">print</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"Not equal\"</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">end</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) They are equal",
            "b) Not equal",
            "c) Nil",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Anything in double quotes is treated as string.\n\n\nOutput:\narray[5]\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 148,
        "Question": "9. What will be the output of the following?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\">array1 = <span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">2</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span>\narray2 = <span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">0</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">0</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">if</span> array1 <span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span>= array2\n<span class=\"kw3\">print</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"Greater or equal\"</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">else</span> \n    <span class=\"kw3\">print</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"Not equal\"</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">end</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Greater or equal",
            "b) Not equal",
            "c) Error",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Two arrays are said to be equal if each and every element of both the arrays are equal.\n\n\nOutput:\nNot equal\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 149,
        "Question": "10. What will be the output of the following?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\">array1 = <span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">2</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span>\narray2 = <span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">0</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">0</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">if</span> array1 == array2\n<span class=\"kw3\">print</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"Equal\"</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">else</span> \n    <span class=\"kw3\">print</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"Not equal\"</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">end</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Equal",
            "b) Not equal",
            "c) Error",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Two arrays are said to be equal if each and every element of both the arrays are equal.\n\n\nOutput:\nThey are equal\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 150,
        "Question": "2. What is the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\">string_array = <span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"st0\">\"a\"</span>,<span class=\"st0\">\"e\"</span>,<span class=\"st0\">\"i\"</span>,<span class=\"st0\">\"o\"</span>,<span class=\"st0\">\"u\"</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span>\n<span class=\"kw3\">print</span> string_array</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) [“a”,”e”,”i”,”o”,”u”].",
            "b) Error",
            "c) Vowels",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Arrays of strings, numbers, booleans can be made."
    },
    {
        "id": 151,
        "Question": "3. What is the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\">string_array = <span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"st0\">\"a\"</span>,<span class=\"st0\">\"e\"</span>,<span class=\"st0\">\"i\"</span>,<span class=\"st0\">\"o\"</span>,<span class=\"st0\">\"u\"</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span>\n<span class=\"kw3\">print</span> string_array<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) [“a”,”e”,”i”,”o”,”u”].",
            "b) Error",
            "c) o",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The array is a string array.\n\n\t\n\n\nOutput:\n[\"a\",\"e\",\"i\",\"o\",\"u\"]\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 152,
        "Question": "a) [“a”,”e”,”i”,”o”,”u”].",
        "Options": [
            "b) Error",
            "c) o",
            "   False",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The array is a string array and the index is 3 so ‘o’ will be the output and then the boolean_array will get printed.\n\n\t\n\n\nOutput:\no\nTrue\nFalse\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 153,
        "Question": "6. What is the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\">a=<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">2</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">3</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">4</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span>\nb=<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">2</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">4</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">6</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">8</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">if</span> a<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span>==b<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">print</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"Equal\"</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">end</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Equal",
            "b) Error",
            "c) 4",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The array is a string array and the index is 3 so ‘o’ will be the output.\n\n        \n\n\nOutput:\no\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 154,
        "Question": "7. What is the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\">a=<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">2</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">3</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">4</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span>\nb=<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">2</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">3</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">4</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">if</span> a==b\n    <span class=\"kw3\">print</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"Equal\"</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">else</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">print</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"Not equal\"</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">end</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Equal",
            "b) Error",
            "c) Not equal",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The array is a string array and the index is 3 so ‘o’ will be the output and then the boolean_array[1] = false will get printed.\n\n\nOutput:\no\nFalse\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 155,
        "Question": "8. What is the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\">a=<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"st0\">\"hey\"</span>, <span class=\"st0\">\"ruby\"</span>, <span class=\"st0\">\"language\"</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span>\nb=<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"st0\">\"hey\"</span>, <span class=\"st0\">\"ruby\"</span>, <span class=\"st0\">\"language\"</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">if</span> a==b\n    <span class=\"kw3\">print</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"Equal\"</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">else</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">print</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"Not equal\"</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">end</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Equal",
            "b) Error",
            "c) Not equal",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: a[3]=4 and b[2]=4 hence it will print equal according to the given if condition.\n\n\nOutput:\nEqual\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 156,
        "Question": "9. What is the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\">a=<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"st0\">\"hey\"</span>, <span class=\"st0\">\"ruby\"</span>, <span class=\"st0\">\"language\"</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span>\nb=<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"st0\">\"hey\"</span>, <span class=\"st0\">\"language\"</span>, <span class=\"st0\">\"ruby\"</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">if</span> a==b\n    <span class=\"kw3\">print</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"Equal\"</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">else</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">print</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"Not equal\"</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">end</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Equal",
            "b) Error",
            "c) Not equal",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Elements of both the array are same hence they are equal.\n\n\nOutput:\nEqual\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 157,
        "Question": "a) 3 ruby",
        "Options": [
            "b) Error",
            "c) 2",
            "   language",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Elements of both the array are same and in same sequence hence they are equal.\n\n\nOutput:\nEqual\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 158,
        "Question": "2. What is the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\">multi_d_array = <span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">0</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">0</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">0</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span>,<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">0</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">0</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">0</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span>,<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">0</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">0</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">0</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span>,<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">0</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">0</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">0</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span>\n<span class=\"kw3\">print</span> multi_d_array</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) [[0, 0, 0, 0], [0, 0, 0, 0], [0, 0, 0, 0], [0, 0, 0, 0]].",
            "b) [0, 0, 0, 0].",
            "c) [0, 0, 0, 0][0, 0, 0, 0].",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: We can put anything in an array and make it array of arrays."
    },
    {
        "id": 159,
        "Question": "4. What is the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\">array1 = <span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">2</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">3</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">4</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span>,<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">0</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">0</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">0</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span>\narray2 = <span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">2</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span>,<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">0</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">0</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">0</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">if</span> array1==array2\n    <span class=\"kw3\">print</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"Equal\"</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">else</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">print</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"Not equal\"</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">end</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) [[1, 2, 3, 4], [0, 0, 0, 0]].",
            "b) Equal",
            "c) Not equal",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Array inside array is declared and then printed.\n\n\n\t\n\n        \n\nOutput:\n[[0, 0, 0, 0], [0, 0, 0, 0], [0, 0, 0, 0], [0, 0, 0, 0]]\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 160,
        "Question": "5. What is the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\">array1 = <span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">2</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">3</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">4</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span>,<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">0</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">0</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">0</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span>\narray2 = <span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">2</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">3</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">4</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span>,<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">0</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">0</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">0</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">if</span> array1==array2\n    <span class=\"kw3\">print</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"Equal\"</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">else</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">print</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"Not equal\"</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">end</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) [[1, 2, 3, 4], [0, 0, 0, 0]].",
            "b) Equal",
            "c) Not equal",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Array inside array is declared and then printed and .each is the iterator used.\n\n\n\t\n\nOutput:\n[1, 2, 3, 4]\n[0, 0, 0, 0]\n[[1, 2, 3, 4], [0, 0, 0, 0]]\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 161,
        "Question": "6. What is the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\">array1 = <span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">2</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">3</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">4</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span>,<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">0</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">0</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">0</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span>\narray2 = <span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">2</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">3</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">4</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span>,<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">0</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">0</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">0</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span>\n<span class=\"kw3\">print</span> array1<span class=\"sy0\">+</span>array2</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) [[1, 2, 3, 4], [0, 0, 0, 0]].",
            "b) [[1, 2, 3, 4], [0, 0, 0, 0], [1, 2, 3, 4], [0, 0, 0, 0]].",
            "c) [[2,4,6,8],[0,0,0,0]].",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Number of elements in both the arrays are not same hence they are unequal\n\n\nOutput:\nNot equal\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 162,
        "Question": "7. What is the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\">array1 = <span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">2</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">3</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">4</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span>,<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">0</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">0</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">0</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span>\narray2 = <span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">2</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">3</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">4</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span>,<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">0</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">0</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">0</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span>\n<span class=\"kw3\">print</span> array1<span class=\"sy0\">-</span>array2</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) [[1, 2, 3, 4], [0, 0, 0, 0]].",
            "b) [[1, 2, 3, 4], [0, 0, 0, 0], [1, 2, 3, 4], [0, 0, 0, 0]].",
            "c) [].",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Number of elements in both the arrays are same hence they are unequal\n\n\nOutput:\nEqual\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 163,
        "Question": "8. What is the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\">array1 = <span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">2</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">3</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">4</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span>,<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">0</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">0</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">0</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span>\narray2 = <span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">2</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">3</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">4</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span>,<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">0</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">0</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">0</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span>\n<span class=\"kw3\">print</span> array1<span class=\"sy0\">*</span>array2</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) [[1, 2, 3, 4], [0, 0, 0, 0]].",
            "b) [[1, 2, 3, 4], [0, 0, 0, 0], [1, 2, 3, 4], [0, 0, 0, 0]].",
            "c) [].",
            "d) Error"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: By adding two arrays we mean appending those two arrays.\n\n\nOutput:\n[[1, 2, 3, 4], [0, 0, 0, 0], [1, 2, 3, 4], [0, 0, 0, 0]]\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 164,
        "Question": "9. What is the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\">array1 = <span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">2</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">3</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">4</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span>,<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">0</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">0</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">0</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span>\narray2 = <span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">2</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span>,<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">0</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">0</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span>\n<span class=\"kw3\">print</span> array1 <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;&amp;</span> array2</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) [[1, 2, 3], [0, 0, 0]].",
            "b) [[1, 2, 3, 4], [0, 0, 0, 0], [1, 2, 3, 4], [0, 0, 0, 0]].",
            "c) [].",
            "d) Error"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: We get an empty array by subtracting two arrays of same elements\n\n\nOutput:\n[]\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 165,
        "Question": "10. What is the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\">array1 = <span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">2</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">3</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">4</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span>,<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">0</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">0</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">0</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span>\narray2 = <span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">2</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span>,<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">0</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">0</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span>\n<span class=\"kw3\">print</span> array1 <span class=\"sy0\">||</span> array2</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) [[1, 2, 3], [0, 0, 0]].",
            "b) [[1, 2, 3, 4, 5], [0, 0, 0, 0]].",
            "c) [].",
            "d) Error"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: We can’t directly multiply elements of array, it will show an error\n\n\nOutput:\ncan't convert Array into Integer\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 166,
        "Question": "11. What is the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\">array1 = <span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">2</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">3</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">4</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span>,<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">0</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">0</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">0</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span>\narray2 = <span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">2</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span>,<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">0</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">0</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span>\n<span class=\"kw3\">print</span> !array1</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) [[1, 2, 3], [0, 0, 0]].",
            "b) [[1, 2, 3, 4, 5], [0, 0, 0, 0]].",
            "c) False",
            "d) Error"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Anding two arrays will give the common elements in both the arrays.\n\n\nOutput:\n[[1, 2, 3], [0, 0, 0]]\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 167,
        "Question": "12. What is the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\">a=<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"st0\">\"a\"</span>,<span class=\"st0\">\"b\"</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span>\nb=<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"st0\">\"e\"</span>,<span class=\"st0\">\"a\"</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span>\n<span class=\"kw3\">print</span> a <span class=\"sy0\">+</span> b</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) [[“a”, “b”], [“e”, “a”]].",
            "b) [[“2a”, “b”], [“e”]].",
            "c) False",
            "d) Error"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Oring two arrays will give the maximum number common and uncommon elements in both the arrays.\n\n\nOutput:\n[[1, 2, 3, 4, 5], [0, 0, 0, 0]]\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 168,
        "Options": [
            "This set of Ruby Programming Interview Questions and Answers for Experienced people focuses on “Introduction to Hashes”.",
            "1. It is possible to make array of booleans.",
            "a) True",
            "b) False"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Arrays of strings, numbers, booleans can be made."
    },
    {
        "id": 169,
        "Question": "2. What is the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\">string_array = <span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"st0\">\"a\"</span>,<span class=\"st0\">\"e\"</span>,<span class=\"st0\">\"i\"</span>,<span class=\"st0\">\"o\"</span>,<span class=\"st0\">\"u\"</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span>\n<span class=\"kw3\">print</span> string_array</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) [“a”,”e”,”i”,”o”,”u”].",
            "b) Error",
            "c) Vowels",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The array is a string array.\n\n\t\n\n\nOutput:\n[\"a\",\"e\",\"i\",\"o\",\"u\"]\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 170,
        "Question": "3. What is the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\">string_array = <span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"st0\">\"a\"</span>,<span class=\"st0\">\"e\"</span>,<span class=\"st0\">\"i\"</span>,<span class=\"st0\">\"o\"</span>,<span class=\"st0\">\"u\"</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span>\n<span class=\"kw3\">print</span> string_array<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) [“a”,”e”,”i”,”o”,”u”].",
            "b) Error",
            "c) o",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The array is a string array and the index is 3 so ‘o’ will be the output.\n\n        \n\n\nOutput:\no\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 171,
        "Question": "a) [“a”,”e”,”i”,”o”,”u”].",
        "Options": [
            "b) Error",
            "c) o",
            "   False",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The array is a string array and the index is 3 so ‘o’ will be the output and then the boolean_array[1] = false will get printed.\n\n\nOutput:\no\nFalse\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 172,
        "Question": "6. What is the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\">a=<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">2</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">3</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">4</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span>\nb=<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">2</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">4</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">6</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">8</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">if</span> a<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span>==b<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">print</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"Equal\"</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">end</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Equal",
            "b) Error",
            "c) 4",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The array is a string array and the index is 3 so ‘o’ will be the output and then the boolean_array will get printed.\n\n\nOutput:\no\nTrue\nFalse\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 173,
        "Question": "7. What is the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\">a=<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">2</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">3</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">4</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span>\nb=<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">2</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">3</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">4</span>,<span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">if</span> a==b\n    <span class=\"kw3\">print</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"Equal\"</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">else</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">print</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"Not equal\"</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">end</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Equal",
            "b) Error",
            "c) Not equal",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: a[3]=4 and b[2]=4 hence it will print equal according to the given if condition.\n\n\nOutput:\nEqual\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 174,
        "Question": "8. What is the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\">a=<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"st0\">\"hey\"</span>, <span class=\"st0\">\"ruby\"</span>, <span class=\"st0\">\"language\"</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span>\nb=<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"st0\">\"hey\"</span>, <span class=\"st0\">\"ruby\"</span>, <span class=\"st0\">\"language\"</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">if</span> a==b\n    <span class=\"kw3\">print</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"Equal\"</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">else</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">print</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"Not equal\"</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">end</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Equal",
            "b) Error",
            "c) Not equal",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Elements of both the array are same hence they are equal.\n\n\nOutput:\nEqual\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 175,
        "Question": "9. What is the output of the given code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"ruby\"><pre class=\"de1\">a=<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"st0\">\"hey\"</span>, <span class=\"st0\">\"ruby\"</span>, <span class=\"st0\">\"language\"</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span>\nb=<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"st0\">\"hey\"</span>, <span class=\"st0\">\"language\"</span>, <span class=\"st0\">\"ruby\"</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">if</span> a==b\n    <span class=\"kw3\">print</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"Equal\"</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">else</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">print</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"Not equal\"</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">end</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Equal",
            "b) Error",
            "c) Not equal",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Elements of both the array are same and in same sequence hence they are equal.\n\n\nOutput:\nEqual\n\n\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 176,
        "Question": "a) 3 ruby",
        "Options": [
            "b) Error",
            "c) 2",
            "   language",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Elements of both the array are same but not in same sequence hence they are not equal.\n\n\nOutput:\nNot equal\n\n\n"
    }
]